Guide to the Peter Schwartz papers, 1981-2000.
Schwartz, Peter papers, 1981-2000
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Peter Schwartz papers, 1981-2000.
23-19-3239
Peter Schwartz
1 cubic ft.
Notes, papers, articles.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes lecture notes, papers, and articles by Schwartz pertaining to his work with fibers and his career in the Dept. of Textiles and Apparel. Also undergraduate papers from students in the Honors Program in the College of Human Ecology and from a course entitled "Investigative Research on the Social Impact of Science".
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Emeritus Professor of Textiles and Apparel, Cornell University, from 1982-2000.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes lecture notes, papers, and articles by Schwartz pertaining to his work with fibers and his career in the Dept. of Textiles and Apparel. Also undergraduate papers from students in the Honors Program in the College of Human Ecology and from a course entitled "Investigative Research on the Social Impact of Science".
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schwartz, Peter; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Dept. of Textiles and Apparel.
Subjects:
Textile fiber industry.; Textiles and Apparel--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Publications
Series II. Course Materials
Series III. Undergraduate Research Papers
A. Undergraduate Research Papers
B. Reports
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Publications
  - Articles and Papers by Peter Schwartz (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Thesis for PhD at North Carolina University 1981: The Mechanical Behavior of Fabrics Having Three, Nonorthogonal Thread Directions (Trixial) and the Equivalence of Conventional Fabrics (Box 1)
  - Report by Harold Robinson, Peter Schwartz and S. Leigh Phoenix Feb. 1987: Experiments on the Strength and Creep-Rupture of Carbon/Epoxy Microcomposites (Box 1)
  - Polymer Outreach Symposium at Cornell in May of 2000- Session by Schwartz entitled: Spinning Fine Polymeric Fibers from Solution and the Melt Using an Electrostatic Field (Box 1)
  - Slides of campus scenes taken by Peter Schwartz (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Course Material
  - Lecture notes from textiles courses (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Lecture notes from TXA Mechanical Reliability Course, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes from TXA 235 - Fibers, Fabrics and Finishes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes from TXA 639 - Mech. Fibrous Structure (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charts - Spun Yarn and Filament Yarn (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Composite course material for MAE 615, TAM 797, MSE 615, Spring 1986 (Box 1)
- Series III: Undergraduate Research Papers
  - A. Undergraduate Research Forum Papers:
    - Proceedings of the Third Annual Undergraduate Research Forum - summer, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Undergraduate Research Forum - summer, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Proceedings of the Fifth Annual Undergraduate Research Forum - summer, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Proceedings of the Fifth Annual Undergraduate Research Forum - spring and summer, 1994 (Box 1)
  - B. Final Papers from the course: Investigative Research on the Social Impact of Science: A course taught in Biology and Society, TXA and sometimes Science and Technology Studies
    - Bio and S 300 and TXA 301, 1991, Spring 1992 (Box 1)
    - Bio and S 300, TXA 301 and S and TS; 402, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Bio and S 300, TXA 301 and S and TS; 402, 1994 (Box 1)